Good morning. I'm Dr. Martin. What's your name?
Juan de la Cruz.
Juan de la Cruz. How old are you?
I'm 30 years old.
What's the reason you went to the emergency room? What are you going to see?
My stomach hurts since this morning.
This morning? Okay. What did you eat last before your stomach hurt? What are you doing?
Actually, last night, my friends and I drank.
When I got home, I didn't eat anything.
But when I woke up this morning, because of my hangover, I had coffee.
Okay. What did you drink last night?
Hard liquor like vodka and tequila.
Okay. Can you estimate how many glasses or bottles you drank last night?
What I remember is we drank two shots of tequila and two shots of vodka.
Okay. But yesterday, you didn't feel anything? You didn't vomit?
Yesterday, I didn't feel anything. I went home and I didn't feel anything.
Okay. What time did you wake up earlier?
Earlier, I woke up at 5 o'clock because of my hangover.
I decided to have coffee.
After I had coffee, that's where my stomach hurt.
Okay. It's now 8 o'clock.
Okay. So if it's 5 o'clock, it's been three hours since you started feeling it.
Then you drank coffee.
Okay. Which part of your stomach hurts?
The part I feel the most is the upper part of my heart.
The lower part?
Yes.
Okay. If you were to give a score of how much it hurts, from 1 to 10, 10 is very painful, 5 is a bit, 0 is nothing.
What is your pain score for now?
For now, 7 out of 10.
Ah, so it's really painful.
Do you feel pain in the back or just in the middle? Just there in your stomach?
It used to hurt in the back, but now it's more in the middle.
Okay. Can you describe the pain? Is it painful? Is it like being stabbed? Is it like being beaten? What is the description of the pain?
Now, it's like it's painful. It's like I want to puke and it hurts a bit.
Then it goes on, right? It doesn't disappear, it comes back, right?
Yes.
Okay. Aside from the pain of the stomach now, do you feel pain in the stomach? Is it hard to rest? Is it painful in the stomach? What do you feel?
There is no pain in the stomach, but it's like I'm catching my breath, it's like I'm choking.
Okay.
But apart from that, there is no continued vomiting.
How is your pooping?
When I got home last night, I just pooped once, but this morning, there is still no chance of pooping.
But these past days, your poops are not black.
What past days? I don't have any. My poop is normal.
Your poop is normal?
Yes.
Okay. Are you sick?
I'm sick, I don't have any.
You don't have any? Okay. Aside from this, do you have any other diseases like high blood, diabetes?
I don't have high blood or diabetes.
Did you go to the hospital recently?
I don't have any.
Did you get operated?
Do you have any allergies to food or medicine?
I don't have any.
Do you have a sore throat?
You don't have any.
But how is drinking alcohol? Do we drink a lot?
To be honest, almost every week, we go out with friends to drink.
This habit has been around for years.
Okay. So how many times a week is this?
In one week, we go out almost every other day.
That's also the case with the consumption of alcohol.
Yes, that's where we play. Sometimes it's more, sometimes it's less. But that's the average.
Okay.
This is just a standard question. Is the use of drugs prohibited?
I haven't tried anything that prohibits drugs.
Okay.
But in your family, how is it? Is there a type of high blood, diabetes?
On my father's website, there's a history of high blood.
On my mother's website, it's diabetes.
Okay.
So for now, we're going to examine you.
I'll get your vital signs. We'll just repeat it.
Okay.
So your BP right now, let's just check.
So it's 120 over 80, sir. So your BP is normal.
Your heart rate is 80 beats per minute.
Then your respiratory rate is at 18 cycles per minute, which is normal.
Your temperature is 36.5, which is normal. You don't have a fever right now.
Your level of oxygen is also good at 98%.
Okay.
I'll just examine you, sir.
I'll just look at your eyes. They're not bluish.
They're not pale either.
So you have anectaric sclera, pink palpebral conjunctiva,
no nasooral discharge,
no neck vein distension,
no anterior neck mass,
no perioral,
no ulitions,
no tonsiloparyngeal congestion.
Okay. Moving on.
I'll just examine your chest.
Symmetrical chest expansion, clear breath sounds,
no wheeze, no crackles,
normal rate, regular rhythm, no murmur,
soft, flat abdomen,
with minimal tenderness and epigastric area.
And then full equal pulses with CRT of less than two seconds.
Okay.
Now for my current assessment as acid peptic disease,
rollout acute pancreatitis.
Now for our plan, I'll be inserting an IV axis,
gauge 20,
and then I will hook my patient to a plain NSS at 80 cc per hour.
We'll give padtoprazole 40-milligram IV now.
And then I will be requesting for the following diagnostics,
CBC, urinalysis, serum lipase.
And then I will place my patient on NPO.
Okay.
And then we'll observe the patient, monitor the vital signs every hour,
and for serial abdominal exam.
Okay, sir.
So, we'll give you the medicines,
we'll give you the IV,
and then we'll observe you now.
Don't eat too much.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you, though.